Guide to the Cherríe Moraga Papers, 1970-1996
Department of Special Collections
Cherríe Moraga Papers,
1970-1996
Special Collections M0905
Moraga, Cherríe
44 linear ft.
Stanford University. Libraries. Dept. of Special Collections and University Archives.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions:
Series 3 (Journals) is restricted, as are Series 4a (Personal Correspondence) and portions of Series 2 (Manuscripts by Moraga) and Series 6 (Manuscripts by others). In addition, selected items have been restricted and removed to parallel files.
Provenance:
Purchased from Cherríe Moraga, 1996
BIOGRAPHY
Cherríe Moraga, an award-winning playwright, poet and essayist, has received national recognition for her creative and critical writings focussing on racism and classism within the white women's movement, issues of sexuality, lesbianism and cultural and racial identity, as well as homophobia and sexism within Chicano culture. Moraga's involvements as a teacher, gay and lesbian youth advocate, editor, activist and cultural critic have served as a catalyst for her work.
Moraga is perhaps most widely known for the highly-acclaimed anthology, This Bridge Called My Back: Writings by Radical Women of Color, which she co-edited with Gloria Anzaldúa and Loving in the War Years / Lo Que Nunca Pasó Por Sus Labios, a collection of poetry and essays. Her theater productions include "Giving Up the Ghost," "Shadow of a Man," "Heroes and Saints," and "Watsonville: Some Place Not Here." She has most recently written Waiting in the wings: a portrait of a queer motherhood (Firebrand Books, 1997).
Born in Whittier, California in 1952, Moraga attended Immaculate Heart College in Los Angeles, from which she graduated in 1974. Following college she worked for three years as an English teacher in Burbank, California. In 1977 she moved to San Francisco where she attended graduate school in Feminist Studies at San Francisco State University. There, she met Barbara Smith, with whom she was to found the important publishing house Kitchen Table: Women of Color Press in New York in 1981.The Press became a critical voice for feminism from Black, Latina, and Third World perspectives. She has served as an instructor in Women's Studies and Chicano Studies and Creative Writing at San Francisco State University, Stanford University, the University of California at Berkeley, and the University of Massachusetts, Boston.
Moraga received a Theatre Communications Group theatre artist residency grant in 1996, the NEA's Theatre Playwrights' Fellowship in 1993 and two Fund for New American Plays Awards from the John F. Kennedy Center for the Performing Arts. She was awarded the Outlook Foundation Literary Award in 1991, The American Book Award from the Before Columbus Foundation in 1986, and a New York State Creative Arts Public Service Program Grant for Poetry.
Cherríe Moraga lives and works in San Francisco.
CHRONOLOGICAL BIOGRAPHY
1952 September 25 Cher'rie Moraga Lawrence is born in Whittier, California, to Elvira Moraga and Joseph Lawrence.
1970-1974 College at Immaculate Heart College in Los Angeles, graduated in 1974.
1980 Received Master of Arts degree in Feminist Studies at California State University, San Francisco
1981 Cofounds, with Barbara Smith, Kitchen Table: Women of Color Press
1981 Publishes This Bridge Called My Back: Writings by Radical Women of Color
1982 MacDowell Arts Colony fellow, New Hampshire
1983 Wins New York State Community Artist Program award.
1983 Loving in the War Years / Lo Que Nunca Pasó Por Sus Labios published
1983 Cuentos: stories by Latinas is published, edited by Alma Gomez, Cherríe Moraga, and Maríana Romo-Carmona.
1984 Selected as Playwright-in-residence at the Hispanic Playwrights Lab at the INTAR (International Arts Relation) Theater, New York under María Irene Fornes.
1986 Awarded Before Columbus American Book Award for This Bridge Called My Back
1986 Giving Up the Ghost is published
1986-1991 Lecturer of writing and theater in Chicano Studies at University of California, Berkeley.
1988 Esta Puente Mi Espalda (Spanish adaptation of This Bridge Called My Back) is published
1989 Co-edits, with Norma Alarcón and Ana Castillo, Third Woman: The Sexuality of Latinas
1989 Feb. 10 Giving Up the Ghost premiere at Theatre Rhinoceros, San Francisco
1989 April Shadow of a Man produced as part of San Francisco's American Conservatory Theatre's Plays-in-Progress series
1990 Publishes with Fornes Shadow of a Man. Produced at the Eureka Theatre, San Francisco, a co-production with Brava! For Women in the Arts.
1990 Opening of Coatlique's Call, a collaboration with visual artist Guadalupe Garcia
1991 Wins Fund for New American Plays award, A Project of the John F. Kennedy Center for the Performing Arts
1992 Heroes & Saints was commissioned by Los Angeles Theatre Center
1992 Apr. 4 Heroes & Saints premieres at Mission Theater, San Francisco,produced by Brava! For Women in the Arts, directed by Albert Takazauckas
1993 Awarded National Endowment for the Arts' Theater Playwrights Fellowship
1993 The Last Generation published
1994 Heroes & Saints and Other Plays published.
1997 Waiting in the wings: a portrait of a queer motherhood published
SCOPE AND CONTENT
The Cherríe Moraga Papers document the life work of an important lesbian Chicana poet, essayist, and playwright of the 20th century. The papers include Moraga's personal and professional correspondence, journals, collected Feminist and Women of Color serials, drafts, manuscripts and galleys, and final publications of her writings, as well as important essays and reviews of her work.
The papers are divided into 19 series: 1. Publications, 2. Manuscripts, 3. Journals, 4. Correspondence, 5. Gigs, 6. Manuscripts by Others, 7. Publicity, 8. Theater Correspondence, 9. Academic Work, 10. Collector's Publications, 11. Publicity, 12. Electronic Media, 13. Essays and Reviews, 14. Photographs, Posters, and Awards and 15. Oversize
Wherever Moraga's original arrangement of materials was encountered, her order was respected.
SERIES DESCRIPTION
- Series I. Publications
  Cherríe Moraga has been a prolific writer during the 1980s and 1990s. This series houses a copy of each of her publications, arranged alphabetically by books, edited volumes, and journal publications.
- Series II. Manuscripts
  Manuscript drafts of most of Moraga's volumes are housed in Series II, along with research materials, transcripts of interviews, and correspondence related to individual pieces. Copies of manuscripts contained on computer disks which are part of the collection (Series XII.c) have been made and inculded in this series. These are primarily draft versions of "Watsonville." This series has been organized alphabetically.
- Series III. Journals
  Moraga bound journals and miscellaneous personal writings have been marked for restricted use by the author. The journals are arranged chronologically.
- Series IV. Correspondence
  Moraga's correspondence has been arranged into two subseries: a. Personal and b. Business.The business correspondence contains a large grouping of permissions requests to cite, reproduce, or use her work. Permissions requests have been arranged alphabetically by the author and title of the work her writings are to be used in. Moraga's personal correspondence has been restricted by the author.
- Series V. Gigs
  Following indications from the collection, Series V contains Cherríe Moraga's gig files. Gigs comprise reading requests, speaking requests, interviews, and requests for publication, as well as business correspondence pertaining to her travel arrangements. The series is organized alphabetically by institution (where available) of name of correpsondent.
- Series VI. Manuscripts by others
  Manuscripts by others are arranged alphabetically by author.
- Series VII. Cultural Work
  Moraga's interest in various social, political and cultural issues is well documented. This series houses her collected research materials, clippings, and articles relating to certain key issues. It is arranged alphabetically.
- Series VIII. Theater Correspondence, 1990s
  Following her own indications, Cherríe Moraga's correpondence regarding the production of her plays has been kept separate from other business correspondence. It includes profiles and resumes of actors, production notes, infomation about various theater companies. This series is arranged alphabetically.
- Series IX. Academic Work
  Cherríe Moraga kept papers and notes written as a student and lecturer, beginning as early as 1970. The papers are organized roughly chronologically into several groups, notably her undergraduate papers, graduate school work, class notes, teaching materials, as well as teaching materials for DramaDIVAS and Indigena as Scribe.
- Series X. Collector's Publications
  Cherríe Moraga collected a small library of feminist, Chicana, and women of color literary publications, written primarily during the 1980s. Most of these publications were from limited runs and are now out of print. The works are arranged alphabetically by title. Notation has been made if a work by Cherríe Moraga is contained in a volume.
- Series XI. Publicity
  Public readings, announcements of new publications, and other publicity related to Moraga's writings are contained in this series. The work is arranged by the name of specific work being publicized.
- Series XII. Electronic Media
  Series XII is arranged into three sub-series: a. Audiocassettes b. Videocassettes c. Computer Disks
  Each subseries is arranged alphabetically. Box 5 is currently unavailable to research, pending preservation. Paper copies of every file on 3 1/2 inch floppy disks have been made and housed in Series II. Manuscripts.
- Series XIII. Essays and Reviews
  Writings about Moraga's work, productions of her plays, and interviews with the author are contained in this series. They are arranged alphabetically by type. (critical essays, interviews, and reviews)
- Series XIV. Photographs, Posters, and Awards
  The artifactual legacy of Moraga's career as a writer, this collection is organized into the three categories of the series title.
- Series XV. Oversize
CONTAINER LIST
- Series I. Publications
  - Subseries a. Books
    - Esta puente, mi espalda: voces de mujeres tercermundistas en los Estados Unidos / editado por Cherríe Moraga y Ana Castillo; traducido por Ana Castillo y Norma Alarcón. San Francisco: ISM Press, c1988. 19i, 281 p.: ill., ports.; 20 cm. [Translation and adaptation of: This bridge called my back.] 1988 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Giving up the ghost: teatro in two acts / by Cherríe Moraga. 1st edition. Los Angeles: West End Press; 58 p.; 22 cm. 1986 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Giving up the ghost: teatro in two acts / by Cherríe Moraga. 2nd printing. Albuquerque: West End Press; 58 p.; 22 cm. 1991 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Heroes and Saints and other plays / Cherríe Moraga. 1st edition. Albuquerque: West End Press; 149 p.; 23 cm. 1994 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Loving in the war years: lo que nunca pasó por sus labios / Cherríe Moraga. 1st edition. Boston: South End Press; viii, 152 p.; 21 cm. (cloth-bound) 1983 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Loving in the war years: lo que nunca pasó por sus labios / Cherríe Moraga. 1st edition. Boston: South End Press; viii, 152 p.; 21 cm. (paper-bound) 1983 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - The last generation: prose and poetry / Cherríe Moraga. 1st edition. Boston: South End Press; 197 p.; 23 cm. 1993 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - This bridge called my back: writings by radical women of color / edited by Cherríe Moraga and Gloria Anzaldúa; foreward by Toni Cade Bambara. Watertown, Mass.: Persephone Press. xxvi, 261 p.: ill.; 22 cm. 1981 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - This bridge called my back: writings by radical women of color / edited by Cherríe Moraga and Gloria Anzaldúa; foreward by Toni Cade Bambara. 2nd edition. New York: Kitchen Table: Women of Color Press. xxvi, 261 p.: ill.; 22 cm. 1983 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Subseries b. Edited Volumes
    - An ear to the ground: an anthology of contemporary American poetry / edited by Marie Harris and Kathleen Aguero. Athens, GA: University of Georgia Press [includes: "Poema como valentín (or a San Francisco love poem)," pp. 199 - 200] 1989 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Chicana Lesbians: the girls our mothers warned us about / edited by Carla Trujillo. Berkeley: Third Woman Press [includes: "La ofrenda," pp. 3 - 9; "If," p. 69; "Half-breed," p. 95; Yvonne Yarbro-Bejarano, "De-constructing the Lesbian body: Cherríe Moraga's Loving in the war years," pp. 143 - 155; "It's not New York," pp. 157 - 158] 1991 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Cuentos: stories by Latinas / edited by Alma Gómez, Cherríe Moraga, and Maríana Romo-Carmora. New York: Kitchen Table: Women of Color Press [includes: "Sin luz," pp. 136 - 137; "Pesadilla," pp. 182 - 191] [2 copies] 1983 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Feminist studies, critical studies (Theories of contemporary culture, vol. 8) / edited by Teresa de Lauretis. Bloomington: Indiana University Press [includes: "From a long line of Vendidas: Chicanas and Feminism," pp. 173 - 190] 1986 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Irvine Chicano literary prize, 1987 - 1988 / edited by Juan Villegas and Julie Foraker. Irvine: Department of Spanish and Portuguese, University of California at Irvine [includes: "Just vision," "En route para Los Angeles," "Cotati, Califas," Poema como valentín (or a San Francisco love poem)," and "Dreaming of other planets," pp. 29 - 35] 1988 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Lenguas sueltas: poemas / Elba Rosario Sánchez y otras. Santa Cruz: Moving Parts Press [includes: "What I am," unpaginated (p. 24)] 1994 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Lesbian poetry: an anthology / edited by Elly Bulkin and Joan Larkin. Watertown, MA: Persephone Press [includes: "Like I am to no one," "You upset the whole system of this place," "For the color of my mother," and "For Amber," pp. 246 - 252] 1981 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Lesbian studies: present and future / edited by Margaret Cruikshank. Old Westbury, NY: The Feminist Press [includes: "Lesbian Literature: a Third World Feminist perspective," pp. 55 - 69] 1982 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Mother to daughter, daughter to mother: a daybook and reader / edited by Tillie Olsen. Old Westbury, NY: The Feminist Press [includes: "What kind of lover have you made me, mother," p. 60] 1989 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Pleasure and danger: exploring female sexuality (papers presented at the Scholar and the Feminist IX conference, held Apr. 24, 1982 at Barnard College, New York City)/ edited by Carole S. Vance. Boston, London, Melbourne, and Henly: Routledge & Kegan Paul [includes: "La dulce culpa," "What is left," Loving in the war years," Passage," and "The slow dance," pp. 417 - 424] 1989 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Powers of desire: the politics of sexuality / edited by Ann Snitow, Christine Stansell, and Sharon Thompson. New York: Monthly Reivew Press [includes: Amber Hollibaugh and Cherríe Moraga, "What we're rollin around in bed with: sexual silences in Feminism," pp. 394 - 405] 1983 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - The coming out stories / edited by Julia Penelope Stanley and Susan J. Wolfe. Watertown, MA: Persephone Press [includes: "La Güera," pp. 187 - 194] 1980 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Subseries c. Serials
    - Concept: a literary magazine. [includes: "You ease me a half an hour into the night," unpaginated (pp. 28 - 29)] 1977 Spring (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Feminist Studies. -- Vol. 14, no. 3 [includes: Janice Mirikitani, Paula Gunn Allen, Cherríe Moraga, and Audre Lorde, "Against Apartheid," pp. 417 - 452] 1988 Fall (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Frontiers: a journal of women's studies. -- Vol. 12, no. 3 [includes: "Art in America, con Acento," pp. 154 - 160] 1992 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - IKON: creativity and change. -- Second series, no. 1[includes: "The voices of the fallers," pp. 81 - 85] 1982 Fall -1983 Winter (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Quarry West. -- No. 26 [includes: "New Mexico Confession," pp. 111 - 113] 1989 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Rara avis. -- Vol. 1, no. 1 [includes: "You upset the whole system of this place," and "There's no stopping me now," pp. 12 - 14] 1978 Feb. (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Revista Mujeres. -- Vol. 5, No. 2 [includes: "The shadow of a man," pp. 52 - 73] 1988 June (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Signs: journal of women in culture and society. -- Vol. 7, no. 3 [includes: "Comment on Stetson's review of 'The Black Women's issue, Condition: 5'," pp. 727 - 729] 1982 Spring (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Sinister wisdom. -- No. 11 [includes: It's the poverty," pp. 84 - 85] 1979 Fall (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Sinister wisdom. -- No. 19 [includes: Michelle Cliff, "Making soul, creating alchemy," a review of This bridge called my back: writings by radical women of color, pp. 26 - 31] 1982 Winter (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Sinister wisdom. -- No. 24 [includes: "Until they burn all the books," pp. 143 - 150] 1983 Fall (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Sinister wisdom. -- No. 43/44 [includes: It's the poverty," pp. 112 - 113] 1991 (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - Americas Review, The. -- Vol. 14, no. 2 [includes: Luz María Umpierre, "With Cherríe Moraga," pp. 54 - 67] 1986 Summer (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Americas Review, The. -- Vol. 15, no. 2 [includes book reviews of Giving up the ghost by Jorge Huerta (in English) and Raquel Aguilaú de Murphy (in Spanish), pp. 104 - 107] 1987 Summer (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - Berkeley Poetry Review. -- No. 23/24 [includes: "Blood Sisters" and "La Huérfana," pp. 78 - 79] 1990 Spring (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - theatre journal. -- Vol. 40, no. 2 [includes: Teresa de Lauretis' "Sexual Indifference and Lesbian Representation" pp. 155-157 and Katherine Cummings' review of Feminist Studies/Critical Studies, ed. Teresa de Lauretis pp. 277-280] 1988 May (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - Third Woman: Texas and More. -- Vol. 3, no. 1 - 2 [includes: Norma Alarcón, "Interview with Cherríe Moraga," pp. 127 - 134; Ana Castillo, review of Alma Gómez, Cherríe Moraga, and Maríana Romo-Carmona, eds. Cuentos: Stories by Latinas; and Ana Castillo, review of Cherríe Moraga's Loving in the war years, lo que nunca pasó por sus labios, pp. 137 - 138] 1989 (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - Third Woman: The sexuality of Latinas / edited by Norma Alarcón, Ana Castillo, and Cherríe Moraga. -- Vol. 4 [Berkeley: Third Woman Press] [includes: "Algo secretamente amado," a review of Borderlands / La Frontera: the new Mestiza, by Gloria Anzaldúa, and "The obedient daughter," a review of Trini, by Estela Portillo Trambley, pp. 151 - 162] 1989 (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - Thirteenth Moon. -- Vol. 6, no. 1/2 [includes: "Fear, a Love Poem", pp. 100-101] 1982 (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - Thirteenth Moon. -- Vol. 7, no. 1/2 (2 copies) [includes: "The Slow Dance" pp. 46-47] 1983 (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - Women Talking/ Women Listening. -- Vol. 4 [includes: "Paranoia", p.11] 1978 (Box 3, Folder 17)
    - Zyzzyva. -- Vol. 6, no.1 [includes: "Credo", pp.121-122] 1990 Spring (Box 3, Folder 18)
    - Zyzzyva. -- Vol. 6, no. 4 [includes: selection from "Shadow of Man" pp. 102-106] 1990 Winter (Box 3, Folder 19)
    - Crossroads. -- No. 31 [includes: "For an Art of Resistance" pp. 2-5] 1993 May (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Equal Means: Women Organizing Economic Solutions. -- Vol. 1, no. 4 1993 Winter (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Fem: Publicatión Feminista. -- No. 34 [includes: "La güera" pp. 11-14] 1984 junio-julio (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Foothill Inter City Newspapers -- Duarte High School girls' sports. n.d. (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Girlfriends. -- Vol. 1, no. 2 [includes: "La Ofrenda" pp. 40-41, 46] 1994 Sept.-Oct. (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Heresies: A Feminist Publication on Art and Politics. -- Vol. 3, no. 4, issue 12 [includes: Amber Hollibaugh and C. Moraga. "What we're rollin around in bed with: Sexual Silences in Feminism: A conversation toward ending them" pp. 58-62] 1981 (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Immaculate Heart College Literary Journal: Grendel II. [includes: "Star City Carny", p.2] 1973 April (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Immaculate Heart College Literary Journal: Grendel's Dam. 1973 May (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Immaculate Heart College Literary Journal: The Bride of Grendel's Dam Jr. [includes: "3 by Cher'rie Lawrence", p.4] 1974 June (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - Miscellaneous articles [Off Our Backs. 1982 July "Played between white hands," Barnard Sexuality Conference. p. 23; Plexus. 1978 June "Wild Iris: Four Years On," p. 13 ;The Great Midwestern Bookshow. 1984 "By Word of Mouth," pp. 6, 16 Feminist Studies. -- Vol. 14, no. 3 1988 Fall "Against Apartheid" (with Janice Mirikitani, Paula Gunn Allen, and Audre Lorde) pp. 417-452; Visiones de la Raza: Chicano Latino Monthly News. -- Vol. 8, no. 4 April "Winter of Oppression, 1982" p. 3 Humanizarte. "Ya Vas, Carnal," p. 7] 1978-1988, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - Outlook: National Lesbian and Gay Quarterly. -- Vol. 1, no. 4 [includes: "The Shadow of a man: stage play in three acts" and interview, pp. 46-57] 1989 Winter (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - Outlook: National Lesbian and Gay Quarterly. -- Vol. 3, no. 2 [includes: "La Ofrenda" pp. 50-53] 1990 Fall (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - Radical Teacher. -- No. 24 [includes: Moraga and Barbara Smith: "Lesbian Literature: A Third World Feminist Perspective" pp. 12-14, 27] [1983?] (Box 4, Folder 13)
    - Theatreforum. -- No. 3 [includes: Jorge Huerta: "Professionalizing Teatro: An overview of Chicano Theatre... " pp. 54-59] [1983?] (Box 4, Folder 14)
- Series II. Manuscripts
  - "Algo secretamente amado": A Review of Gloria Anzaldua's Borderlands/La Frontera: The New Mesteza. 1988 Fall (Box 1, Folder 1)
    1 TMs, 5pp.
  - Art in America con Acento n.d. (Box 1, Folder 2)
    2 TMs, 10 -12 pp.
  - "Blood Sisters" n. d. (Box 1, Folder 3)
    3 TMs
  - "Blood Sisters" and "Hermit's prayer," Matrix.--Vol. 15, no. 7 (1991 Oct.): 16 1991 Oct. (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Brava! Biographical statement 1991 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - This Bridge Called My Back. TOC, Preface, Introduction. n. d. (Box 1, Folder 6)
    4 TMs
  - This Bridge Called My Back. "And When You Leave, Take Your Pictures With You." [1 of 3] n. d. (Box 1, Folder 7)
    6 TMs
  - This Bridge Called My Back. "And When You Leave, Take Your Pictures With You." [2 of 3] n. d. (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - This Bridge Called My Back. "And When You Leave, Take Your Pictures With You." [3of 3] [includes TMs, original draft of Audre Lorde's "The Master's Tools will never dismantle the Master's House"] n. d. (Box 1, Folder 9)
    5 TMs
  - This Bridge Called My Back. "Children Passing in the Streets" n. d. (Box 1, Folder 10)
    8 TMs
  - This Bridge Called My Back. "Entering the Lives of Others" n. d. (Box 1, Folder 11)
    9 TMs
  - This Bridge Called My Back. "Between the Lines: On Culture, Class, and Homophobia" pp. 149-231 n. d. (Box 1, Folder 12)
    1 TMs: 82 pp.
  - This Bridge Called My Back. "Between the Lines" n. d. (Box 1, Folder 13)
    2 TMs
  - This Bridge Called My Back. "Between the Lines" n. d. (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - This Bridge Called My Back."Between the Lines" n. d. (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - This Bridge Called My Back. "Speaking in Tongues: The Third World Woman Writer"; pp. 232-275. n. d. (Box 1, Folder 16)
    1 TMs, 43 pp.
  - This Bridge Called My Back. "Speaking in Tongues" n. d. (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - This Bridge Called My Back. "El Mundo Surdo: The Vision" pp. 276-351 n. d. (Box 1, Folder 18)
    1 TMs, 75 pp.
  - This Bridge Called My Back. "El Mundo Zurdo" [1 of 3] [original paste-up of "La Prieta"] n. d. (Box 2, Folder 1)
    TMs, 16 pp.
  - This Bridge Called My Back. "El Mundo Zurdo" [2 of 3] [duplicate of paste-up of "La Prieta"] n. d. (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - This Bridge Called My Back. "El Mundo Zurdo" [3 of 3] n. d. (Box 2, Folder 3)
    2 TMs, 3 pp.
  - This Bridge Called My Back. "El Mundo Zurdo" n. d. (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - This Bridge Called My Back. "El Mundo Zurdo" [original paste-up of Luisah Teish] n. d. (Box 2, Folder 5)
    TMs